JEFF D. MEAD

Software Development

Phone: 908-229-2034

Email: Jeffdmead171@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/JMead171

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jeff-mead-58b6b8136/

Twitter: twitter.com/JDM_Management

Pursuing a position in software development with a professional organization that will challenge and use my talents and experience for both mutual growth and success. Experienced in Javascript programming; developing, testing and debugging code; designing interfaces; and administering systems and networks. Quickly learn and master new technologies; successful working in both team and self-directed settings. Have a MBA in business administration and over 10 years of business operational experience.

Languages & Proficiency

JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js Express.js, GitHub, MySQL, MongoDB GIT, APIs, MVC, VS Code, COBOL

Hard Skills

Coding, Debugging, Program Analyst Software Development, Researching

Soft Skills

Business Acumen, Leadership Personnel Management

Experience

Freelance Software Developer

2020

Writing, refactoring, optimizing and debugging code across multiple applications to ensure the functionality of the code is
working efficiently and correctly. Researching and Analyzing new concepts and programming languages for enhancing
future projects. Major areas of training include: Javascript, CSS, HTML, Node.js. GitHub, GIT, SQL and NoSQL,
MongoDB, MySQL, APIs, REST, Express.js and MVC.

Business Management/Operations Consultant JDM Management Inc., NJ

2017 to 2020

• Owner and CEO of JDM Management, expert in combining financial, business and technology planning for organizational success. Focused to optimize long-term gains in performance, revenues and profitability for small businesses.

Director of Operations

The Kokes Organization Real Estate Firm, NJ

2003 to 2017

 Managed the daily business operations for a mid-size Real Estate Firm consisting of over 100 employee and over \$10 in annual revenue. Business activities included Sales, Budgeting, Forecasting, Financial Reporting, CRM Software, IT Support, Strategic Planning and Company Financial & Sales Presentations.

Computer Programmer/Analyst

Scudder, Stevens & Clark, New York City, NY

1996 to 2002

 Developed and Managed Programming Projects. Develop and coded computer software for financial systems using COBOL & CICS. In addition, created CICS interface and maintained computer software for the reconciliation of financial transactions between brokerage house and bank institutions. Also, managed overnight batch processing for software and data updates to the financial system.

Education

•	University of Central Florida, FL	Certificate, Coding Bootcamp: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, SQL	2020
•	Monmouth University, NJ	MBA, Business Management & Administration	2011
•	Georgian Court University, NJ,	B.S., Business Management & Administration	1999
•	Brick Computer Science Institute, NJ	Certificate, COBOL, CICS, Mainframe	1995